# REYNALDO E. APONTE DÁVILA

E: reynaldo.emanuel@gmail.com • M: 787-637-6634 • Palo Alto, CA • LinkedIn

# **Full Stack Web Developer**

Passionate about both foreign and programming languages, with working proficiency in Java, Python, Italian, French, and Swift. Experienced in coding, testing and debugging web applications from start to finish. Developed curriculum for range of IT courses including programming fundamentals and web development bootcamps covering entire application design process

#### **SKILLS**

- HTML, CSS, SCSS/SASS, Responsive Web Design

JavaScript, jQuery

- Spring Boot, JPA, Maven

- Microsoft Office Suite

AWS / Heroku

- IntelliJ/Xcode/Dreamweaver

- GitHub VCS

- CLI

MySQL

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Freelance Web Developer

Present - Nov 2022

- Design and deploy web applications from scratch using relational databases.
- Update front-end and UI for existing web applications
- Create, develop and update curricula for multiple IT courses including Java Web Development Boot Camp and Mobile App Development with Swift (iOS).

# Technical Training & Development Coordinator

Nov 2022 - June 2021

Montgomery College, Gaithersburg, MD

- Teach, organize, coordinate, and design IT training for Montgomery College's Workforce Development and Continuing Education programs.
- Identify surrounding communities' skill gaps and nearby businesses' training needs to adjust training curricula to current market-relevant skills.

## **Adjunct Instructor**

Nov 2022 - 2019

Montgomery College, Gaithersburg, MD

- **Java Boot camp** Assist students in learning how to plan, test, debug and optimize their applications as they go from their first Java program through the process to deploying their first live website.
- **Montgomery Can Code** Lead the Montgomery Can Code Club for MCPS students from 6<sup>th</sup>-8<sup>th</sup> grade where students learn to code through Apple's Swift Playgrounds.
- General IT courses Develop, manage, and implement syllabi for a variety of IT courses such as AWS cloud services.

# Foreign Languages Teacher

2018 - 2016

Rosa Bell School, Guaynabo, Puerto Rico

- Taught 3 to 6 Italian and French language and culture classes daily for students in grades 4-12.

## **EDUCATION**

2019 Montgomery College • Gaithersburg, MD

- AWS Boot Camp (55 hours)
- Cyber Security Boot Camp (75 hours),
- Java Web Development Boot Camp (280 hours),
- Front-end Web Developer Certificate (60 hours)

2016 University of Puerto Rico - Rio Piedras, PR

- Bachelor of Arts in Foreign Languages (summa cum laude; GPA 3.9)



